{
    "questions" : [
        {   "sections"      : "※ [1~3] 다음을 듣고 알맞은 그림을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "37_1_img",
            "option_1"      : "①  ",
            "option_2"      : "②  ",
            "option_3"      : "③  ",
            "option_4"      : "④  ",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  ",
            "score"         : "2",
            "isImg"         : "y"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [1~3] 다음을 듣고 알맞은 그림을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "37_2_img",
            "option_1"      : "①  ",
            "option_2"      : "②  ",
            "option_3"      : "③  ",
            "option_4"      : "④  ",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  ",
            "score"         : "2",
            "isImg"         : "y"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [1~3] 다음을 듣고 알맞은 그림을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "37_3_img",
            "option_1"      : "①  ",
            "option_2"      : "②  ",
            "option_3"      : "③  ",
            "option_4"      : "④  ",
            "detail"        : " According to a survey of women in their 30s on where to buy cosmetics, they use cosmetics stores the most. It was followed by department stores and large discount stores, with the number of department store users significantly decreasing compared to last year.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  ",
            "score"         : "2",
            "isImg"         : "y"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [4~8]다음 대화를 잘듣고 이어질 수있는 말을 고르십시오.(각2점)",
            "question"      : "4. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  제시간에 도착해서 다행이야",
            "option_2"      : "②  수업 끝나고 가도 늦지 않아",
            "option_3"      : "③  강연은 누구든지 들을 수 있어",
            "option_4"      : "④  시간이 얼마나 걸릴지 모르겠어",
            "detail"        : "Man : Novelist Park In-soo is coming to school for a lecture today.\nWoman : Yes? What time does it start? I have class until 3 o'clock.\nMan : It's not too late to go after class.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  수업 끝나고 가도 늦지 않아",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [4~8]다음 대화를 잘듣고 이어질 수있는 말을 고르십시오.(각2점)",
            "question"      : "5. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  정말 좋은 기회니까 잘 쉬고 와요",
            "option_2"      : "②  그렇게 하고 싶어하는 줄 몰랐어요",
            "option_3"      : "③  특별히 휴가를 낼 만큼 바빴나 봐요",
            "option_4"      : "④  그래도 가기로 한 건데 잘 해 보세요",
            "detail"        : "Man : Soojin, I heard you're going to do volunteer work starting next week.\nWoman : Yes, I took a vacation because it was something I really wanted to do.\nMan : I didn't know you wanted to do that.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  그렇게 하고 싶어하는 줄 몰랐어요",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [4~8]다음 대화를 잘듣고 이어질 수있는 말을 고르십시오.(각2점)",
            "question"      : "6. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  바꿔 주면 좋겠는데",
            "option_2"      : "②  물어볼 필요는 없겠지",
            "option_3"      : "③  날짜가 지났을지 몰라",
            "option_4"      : "④  빨리 입어 볼 걸 그랬어",
            "detail"        : "Woman : Can I change this because it's past the exchange period?\nMan : I've never worn it, so ask me.\nWoman : I'd like you to change it.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  바꿔 주면 좋겠는데",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [4~8]다음 대화를 잘듣고 이어질 수있는 말을 고르십시오.(각2점)",
            "question"      : "7. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  저도 가게에 가서 사야겠어요",
            "option_2"      : "②  그 집 연락처 좀 알려 주세요",
            "option_3"      : "③  아침을 준비하려면 바쁘겠어요",
            "option_4"      : "④  일할 때 먹을 수 있어서 좋아요",
            "detail"        : "Man : Sumin, do you still deliver breakfast these days?\nWoman : Yeah, it's been about a month. I think it's good to have some time in the morning.\nMan : please tell me the contact information for the house.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  그 집 연락처 좀 알려 주세요",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [4~8]다음 대화를 잘듣고 이어질 수있는 말을 고르십시오.(각2점)",
            "question"      : "8. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  며칠 더 걸릴 것 같습니다",
            "option_2"      : "②  이미 전시회를 시작했습니다",
            "option_3"      : "③  다음 달에 초대하려고 합니다",
            "option_4"      : "④  계획보다 늦게 올 것 같습니다",
            "detail"        : "Woman : It's a plan for the exhibition to be held next month. Please review it.\nMan : Good job, Jiyoung. By the way, is the list of guests for the exhibition organized?\nWoman : I think it'll take a few more days.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  며칠 더 걸릴 것 같습니다",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [9~12]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 여자가 이어서 할행 동으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "9. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  남자에게 번역한 과제를 받는다",
            "option_2"      : "②  남자에게 전화로 번역을 부탁한다",
            "option_3"      : "③  남자에게 이메일로 과제를 보낸다",
            "option_4"      : "④  남자에게 전화해서 제출 날짜를 묻는다",
            "detail"        : "Woman : Are you good at English? I have a translation assignment, can you check if I did it properly?\nWoman : Well, just send it by mail. How long do I have to do this?\nWoman : The assignment is due next Monday, so please send it by Saturday.\nMan : All right. Then I'll call you after checking my mail.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  남자에게 이메일로 과제를 보낸다",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [9~12]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 여자가 이어서 할행 동으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "10. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  사무실에 전화해서 고지서를 받는다",
            "option_2"      : "②  고지서가 있는지 우편함을 확인한다",
            "option_3"      : "③  고지서를 받으러 관리사무소에 간다",
            "option_4"      : "④  우편함에 관리비 고지서를 넣어 둔다",
            "detail"        : "Woman : It's the management office? I haven't received the apartment maintenance bill yet.\nMan : Oh, is that so? Did you check your mailbox by any chance? I put it in yesterday.\nWoman : I saw it, but it wasn't there. Can I get it if I go to the management office now?\nMan : Yes, I'll reissue it as soon as you come. ",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  고지서를 받으러 관리사무소에 간다",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [9~12]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 여자가 이어서 할행 동으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "11. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  차의 속도가 빠른지 확인한다",
            "option_2"      : "②  차에서 내려 바퀴 상태를 본다",
            "option_3"      : "③  카센터에 들러서 차를 점검한다",
            "option_4"      : "④  휴게소로 들어가서 차를 세운다",
            "detail"        : "Women : Minsu, I think the car is shaking a little.\nMan : Really? Isn't it because it's too fast? Slow down a little.\nWomen : It's the same. It hasn't been long since the car center checked... ...but I'll have to stop it.\nMan : If you go a little further, you'll find a rest area. I'll check if there's a problem with the wheels.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  휴게소로 들어가서 차를 세운다",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [9~12]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 여자가 이어서 할행 동으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "12. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  안내를 도와줄 학생을 알아본다",
            "option_2"      : "②  필요한 인원을 정확하게 조사한다",
            "option_3"      : "③  설명회 자료 제작 회사에 전화한다",
            "option_4"      : "④  직원을 만나러 설명회 장소에 간다",
            "detail"        : "Man : Manager Kim, how's the preparation for the new product briefing going?\nWoman : Yes, but the materials for the briefing session haven't arrived yet. We don't have enough people to help us.\nMan : Well, try calling the data company. I'll see if I can find a part-time student to help.\nWoman : Yes, it is. See you later.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  설명회 자료 제작 회사에 전화한다",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [13~16] 다음을 듣고 내용과 일치하는 것을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "13. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  여자는 사진을 한 장 가지고 있다",
            "option_2"      : "②  남자는 여자에게 학생증을 빌려 줬다",
            "option_3"      : "③  도서관에 가면 학생증을 바로 만들어 준다",
            "option_4"      : "④  도서관 출입증을 만들려면 사진이 필요하다",
            "detail"        : "Women : Minsu, I'm sorry, but could you lend me a book at the library? I lost my student ID yesterday.\nMan : When I go to the library, they make me a library pass.\nWomen : A library pass? I don't have a picture... Can you make it for me even if I don't have one?\nMan : They'll take pictures for you in the library. You can make it into that picture.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  도서관 출입증을 만들려면 사진이 필요하다",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [13~16] 다음을 듣고 내용과 일치하는 것을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "14. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  점검을 할 때 비상벨이 울릴 수 있다",
            "option_2"      : "②  불편한 점은 총무과에 전화하면 된다",
            "option_3"      : "③  점검하는 동안 계단으로 가면 안 된다",
            "option_4"      : "④  소방 점검은 두 시간 동안 진행될 것이다",
            "detail"        : "Women : The general affairs department will give you an announcement. We are going to conduct an inspection of the fire fighting facilities from 2 p.m. today. Emergency alarm bells may be activated during the inspection. And you can't use the elevator, so please use the stairs. I'd appreciate your understanding even if it's a little inconvenient. ",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  점검을 할 때 비상벨이 울릴 수 있다",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [13~16] 다음을 듣고 내용과 일치하는 것을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "15. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  복사기 대여 기간은 최대 1년이다",
            "option_2"      : "②  복사기가 고장 나면 수리를 해 준다",
            "option_3"      : "③  복사기 대여는 편리하지만 비경제적이다",
            "option_4"      : "④  복사기를 빌리면 관리비는 본인 부담이다",
            "detail"        : "Man : Next is the news news.There are many inconvenience because I'm a copy of the copy?The service that borrow more than one year, a service that borrow more than one year.The copy management costs are borne by the copy of the copy of the copy.If I borrow a copy, it's about 100 million won per year.This advantage is expected to increase the office to borrow copies. ",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  복사기가 고장 나면 수리를 해 준다",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [13~16] 다음을 듣고 내용과 일치하는 것을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "16. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  이곳은 오래된 문화 공간이다",
            "option_2"      : "②  이곳은 시민들이 직접 사용하고 있다",
            "option_3"      : "③  이곳은 다음 달에 새로 문을 열 계획이다",
            "option_4"      : "④  이곳은 시장을 위한 공간으로 바뀔 것이다",
            "detail"        : "Woman : Mayor, I understand that construction is underway to transform the City Hall Training Center into a cultural space for citizens. Please introduce yourself.\nMan : Yes, the City Hall Training Center is a place that has been empty for several years because of its old facilities. So when I looked into the citizens' thoughts while planning for reconstruction, there were many opinions to use it as a cultural space. In the future, we plan to use this place as a concert hall or event hall. Next month, a new cultural space will be created in our city. ",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  이곳은 다음 달에 새로 문을 열 계획이다",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [17~20] 다음을 듣고 남자의 중심 생각을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "17. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  회사 동호회 활동은 부담스럽다",
            "option_2"      : "②  회사에 동호회가 많았으면 좋겠다",
            "option_3"      : "③  회사 동호회 활동은 직장 생활에 도움이 된다",
            "option_4"      : "④  직장 생활과 동호회 활동은 따로 해야 한다",
            "detail"        : "Man : Sumi, why don't you join the company club?\nWoman : I have a separate club. So I'm not going to join the company club. I thought it would be a bit uncomfortable if I learned about my personal life.\nMan : If you do hobbies together, you can get close to people at work quickly. You can get advice when you need it.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  회사 동호회 활동은 직장 생활에 도움이 된다",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [17~20] 다음을 듣고 남자의 중심 생각을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "18. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  기념우표는 전시회에서 발행된다",
            "option_2"      : "②  기념우표는 역사적 의미를 담고 있다",
            "option_3"      : "③  기념우표를 전시하는 것은 역사적인 일이다",
            "option_4"      : "④  기념우표를 보여주는 것은 의미 있는 일이다",
            "detail"        : "Man : This must be a commemorative Olympic stamp issued so far.\nWoman : Yeah. That's really cool. I think it shows the history of the Olympics.\nMan : Actually, I didn't quite understand why they were issuing commemorative stamps. But after coming to the exhibition, I understand the meaning. I think it has a great historical value.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  기념우표는 역사적 의미를 담고 있다",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [17~20] 다음을 듣고 남자의 중심 생각을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "19. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  역사 드라마는 시청률에 의존한다",
            "option_2"      : "②  역사 드라마는 사실 전달이 중요하다",
            "option_3"      : "③  역사 드라마는 역사 공부 자료가 된다",
            "option_4"      : "④  역사 드라마는 작가의 의도대로 제작된다",
            "detail"        : "Man : Isn't that so different from the history of the drama's history? I don't know if the writer knew and wrote it correctly.\nWomen : It's just a drama. I'm sure they've adapted some of the content to make it interesting.\nMan : I think historical dramas should pay more attention to historical facts than ratings. Isn't that what the viewers are looking forward to?\nWoman : That's true, but what viewers want is not studying history, but having fun.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  역사 드라마는 사실 전달이 중요하다",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [17~20] 다음을 듣고 남자의 중심 생각을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "20. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  청소년을 대상으로 국악 교육을 해야 한다",
            "option_2"      : "②  청소년을 위한 국악 공연이 많아져야 한다",
            "option_3"      : "③  청소년들에게 전통 악기를 연주할 기회를 주어야 한다",
            "option_4"      : "④  청소년들이 갖고 있는 국악에 대한 태도를 바꾸어야 한다",
            "detail"        : "Woman : The leader is holding a Korean traditional music performance for teenagers. Do you have any particular reason for performing for young people?\nMan : Yes. Teenagers these days seem to think Korean traditional music is boring. Therefore, it is necessary for young people to easily access and enjoy Korean traditional music. It is to provide an opportunity for young people to play traditional musical instruments by arranging popular songs to match Korean music. I think it's important to break the prejudice against Korean traditional music in this way. So, I plan to continue doing performances for teenagers in the future. ",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  청소년들이 갖고 있는 국악에 대한 태도를 바꾸어야 한다",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [21~22] 다음을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "21. 남자의 중심 생각으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  쇼핑몰은 개인 정보를 잘 관리해야 한다",
            "option_2"      : "②  쇼핑몰에 가입하면 쉽게 개인 정보가 유출된다",
            "option_3"      : "③  개인 정보 유출을 막으려면 본인이 신경 써야 한다",
            "option_4"      : "④  잘 이용하지 않는 쇼핑몰에는 가입하지 말아야 한다",
            "detail"        : "Woman : I got a call that my personal information was leaked from the shopping mall I signed up for before, what should I do?\nMan : Leakage of personal information? I'll go into the homepage and change the password first.\nWoman : I shouldn't have signed up even though I don't use it often. But shouldn't the shopping mall manage personal information more thoroughly? There are so many accidents these days...\nMan : You can't leave all your personal information management to the mall. This wouldn't have happened if you changed your password often.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  개인 정보 유출을 막으려면 본인이 신경 써야 한다",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [21~22] 다음을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "22. 들은 내용으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  여자는 쇼핑몰 가입을 후회하고 있다",
            "option_2"      : "②  여자는 쇼핑몰의 비밀번호를 자주 바꿨다",
            "option_3"      : "③  이 쇼핑몰은 개인 정보 유출 사실을 숨겼다",
            "option_4"      : "④  이 쇼핑몰은 개인 정보 없이 가입할 수 있다",
            "detail"        : "Woman : I got a call that my personal information was leaked from the shopping mall I signed up for before, what should I do?\nMan : Leakage of personal information? I'll go into the homepage and change the password first.\nWoman : I shouldn't have signed up even though I don't use it often. But shouldn't the shopping mall manage personal information more thoroughly? There are so many accidents these days...\nMan : You can't leave all your personal information management to the mall. This wouldn't have happened if you changed your password often.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  여자는 쇼핑몰 가입을 후회하고 있다",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [23~24] 다음을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "23. 남자의 중심 생각으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  야외무대 위치에 대해 알아보고 있다",
            "option_2"      : "②  야외무대 사용에 대해 문의하고 있다",
            "option_3"      : "③  야외무대에서 행사 진행을 도와주고 있다",
            "option_4"      : "④  야외무대에서 상품 홍보를 준비하고 있다",
            "detail"        : "Man : Is it the ward office? I want to use the outdoor stage in front of the park. How do I apply?\nWoman : What event is it? It cannot be used to sell goods or promote products on an outdoor stage.\nMan : Yes, I know. This is a sharing event held by a charitable organization.I will do a stage event for a while and mainly hand out promotional materials to people.\nWoman : Is it? For that purpose, you can apply. The application form can be downloaded from the ward office website. After the event, you must clean up the area.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  야외무대 사용에 대해 문의하고 있다",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [25~26] 다음을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "24. 들은 내용으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  야외무대는 구청에서 관리한다",
            "option_2"      : "②  행사 신청서는 자선 단체에 제출한다",
            "option_3"      : "③  행사 후 주변 청소는 구청에서 해 준다",
            "option_4"      : "④  자선 단체가 물건을 파는 행사를 하려고 한다",
            "detail"        : "Man : Is it the ward office? I want to use the outdoor stage in front of the park. How do I apply?\nWoman : What event is it? It cannot be used to sell goods or promote products on an outdoor stage.\nMan : Yes, I know. This is a sharing event held by a charitable organization.I will do a stage event for a while and mainly hand out promotional materials to people.\nWoman : Is it? For that purpose, you can apply. The application form can be downloaded from the ward office website. After the event, you must clean up the area.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  야외무대는 구청에서 관리한다",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [25~26] 다음을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "25. 남자의 중심 생각으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  자기 계발은 계획서 작성이 필요하다",
            "option_2"      : "②  진정한 자기 계발은 스스로 하는 것이다",
            "option_3"      : "③  자기 평가가 안 좋으면 다시 도전할 수 있다",
            "option_4"      : "④  자기 평가가 안 좋으면 다시 도전할 수 있다",
            "detail"        : "Woman : Sir, I heard that this school has a self-improvement program. Could you briefly introduce it?\nMale : Yes, it's important that self-development programs are self-directed, and so is our school programs. Students decide what they want to do at the beginning of the semester and choose one of them and submit a plan. The school only checks the progress in the middle. Students write reports or meet experts in related fields for interviews. The evaluation is also done on its own at the end of the semester, but if you are not satisfied with the results, you can try again next semester.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  진정한 자기 계발은 스스로 하는 것이다",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [25~26] 다음을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "26. 들은 내용으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  학생들은 스스로 계획서를 작성한다",
            "option_2"      : "②  보고서를 쓰려면 전문가를 만나야 한다",
            "option_3"      : "③  학교가 학생들의 자기 계발 결과를 평가한다",
            "option_4"      : "④  학생들은 학기 말에 자기 계발 계획서를 낸다",
            "detail"        : "Woman : Sir, I heard that this school has a self-improvement program. Could you briefly introduce it?\nMale : Yes, it's important that self-development programs are self-directed, and so is our school programs. Students decide what they want to do at the beginning of the semester and choose one of them and submit a plan. The school only checks the progress in the middle. Students write reports or meet experts in related fields for interviews. The evaluation is also done on its own at the end of the semester, but if you are not satisfied with the results, you can try again next semester.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  학생들은 스스로 계획서를 작성한다",
            "score"         : "2"
        }
        
    ]
   
}
